你觉得它很可爱  对不对
You think this is cute, don't you?
你觉得你们有真正的情感共鸣
You think there's a real connection there.
你喂它吃东西
So you feed it,
给它穿衣服
you dress it up.
九 条 命
但是猫并不在乎你的死活
But a cat doesn't care if you live or die
只要有人每天给它吃两顿饭就行
as long as someone gives it Friskies twice a day.
可是人们极度渴求陪伴
But people are so desperate for someone to hold onto
已经饥不择食
they'll take whatever they can get.
我是在出事后几个月  在街头捡到他的
I found him on the street, months after the accident
我总把他打扮成正雄的样子
and I dress him like Masao.
我知道是我儿子附身在猫上回来找我了
I know my son has come back to me in this cat.
但是不管你有多孤单
But no matter how lonely you are,
猫总归不是人
a cat is not a person.
谢谢  你真会安慰人
Okay. Super helpful, uh...
布兰德航空
市场部希望能把新广告牌投入使用
Oh, so marketing wants sign-off on the new billboard.
梦想成真
你觉得如何
What do you think?
可能修图修得有点狠了
It might be a little heavy on the Photoshop.
来架真正的F16
Get me a real F-16.
拍点真实的照片
We'll take some real pictures.
不  他们说没有这个预算
No, they said they don't have the budget for it.
那就把市场部开了
Fire the marketing department!
你要把整个市场部都开掉吗
You wanna fire the entire marketing department?
不是  我要真正的F16战隼战斗机  下一件事
No. I wanna fly a real F-16. What's next?
你让我提醒你
I'm supposed to remind you,
劳拉留了两条留言
Lara's left two messages.
她为什么打电话
Why is she calling?
因为她是你妻子
Because she's your wife.
之后的媒体见面会
I put together some talking points
我帮你整理了要点
for your press conference.
你多大来着
How old are you again?
28岁
Twenty-eight.
我已经跟媒体打交道28年了
That's how long I've been talking to the press.
放心吧
I'll be fine.
先生  我们准备好了
Sir, we're ready.
不如你今天跟我一起跳吧
Why don't you jump with me today?
算了吧  我刚吃完早餐
Oh, yeah, no. I just had breakfast, so...
来吧
Come on!
爸  不行
Dad, I can't. I can't.
好吧
All right.
胆小鬼
Chicken!
说得真狠  爸
Good one, Dad.
漂亮
Yeah!
非常厉害
Very nice, very nice!
着陆很完美
Perfect landing.
谢谢
Thank you.
谢谢大家  谢谢
Thank you very much. Thank you.
大家上午好
Good morning, everyone.
这里景色太好了
What an incredible view.
我是说一大早见到各位真是赏心悦目
And I mean all of you that I get to look at this fine morning.
谢谢各位抽空前来
Thank you for coming.
等一个月后
Now, when we open this building
这座大楼竣工
one month from today.
布兰德大楼会是北美最高的建筑
The FireBrand Tower will be the tallest building in North America.
也就是说这么多年来被迫在那破地方工作
And that means that we can finally move out of that dump
我们终于可以搬出去了
we've all been forced to work in all these years down the block.
跟我们讲讲芝加哥吧
Tell us about Chicago.
布兰德先生  您对百丽宫大厦有什么看法
Mr. Brand, any comment on the Paragon Tower?
你是说他们在芝加哥堆砌起来的简易房吗
Oh, you mean that tin shack they're gluing together over there in Chicago?
我就不说什么了
No. No comment on that.
据说会比您的大楼高18米左右
Rumor is they're beating you by 60 feet.
不会的  不可能
Well, no. There's not a chance of that.
不会  我非常愿意继续回答问题
No, no. Look, I'd love to answer more questions,
但我得回办公室去了
but I gotta get back to the office.
好的  我希望这个项目做快点
All right. I wanna move fast here.
让法务部连夜把这个看一遍
Have legal review this overnight.
他们一直在忙大楼的事
They're all tied up with the tower.
我知道我们得让他开心
Listen, I know we got to keep him happy,
但是不能让这座大楼耽误我们...
but we can't let this building distract us from...
怎么  你有别的安排吗
Why? You've got something better to do?
媒体见面会顺利吗
How was the press conference?
很显然浪费了我的时间
Well, apparently it was a distraction.
我安排了一些人去考察公开募股的事了
I pulled some staff to explore a public offering.
等等  我让你把我的公司卖掉了吗
I'm sorry. Did I ask you to sell my company?
请问是要投标吗
Are we taking bids?
加利能卖多少钱
How much can we get for Gary?
我们粗略估计了一下...
We ran some rough numbers...
好  首先  为什么媒体在问我芝加哥的事
Yeah. Well, first, why is the press asking me about Chicago?
你占了上风  你的更大
You're winning. Yours is bigger.
新宣传标语终于出来了
Well, finally there's our new slogan.
竣工典礼准备得如何了
Where are we with the opening ceremony?
我们会在整座大楼上装满烟花
We're gonna rig the entire building with fireworks.
所以  我一剪彩
Oh, so, wait. When I cut the ribbon...
烟花就会绽放
Fireworks go off.
天哪  伊恩  这主意太棒了
Oh, my God. Ian, that is just spectacular,
我们又不是在庆祝国庆
you know, if we were doing a Fourth of July celebration
也不是在庆祝啤酒节
or a really rousing Oktoberfest.
汤姆  不能...
Tom, we can't keep...
我们马上就要建成北半球最高的建筑物了
Look, we are just about to cap off the tallest building in the Northern Hemisphere
要是竣工典礼不够宏大我还怎么吹牛逼
and I can't brag about it if I don't own it.
是
Yeah.
真是浪费时间
This is the distraction.
好了  假装刚才什么都没发生
Okay, everybody, let's pretend that that didn't just happen.
-这是什么  -是惊喜
- What's that? - It's a surprise.
我的生日礼物吗
For my birthday?
-你在看什么  -在看爸爸
- What are you watching? - Dad.
他让你录的吗
Did he tell you to record this?
没有  我只是想看他
No, but I just wanted to see him.
你看
Look. Watch.
这么多年来被迫在这破地方工作
And that means that we can finally move out of that dump
终于可以搬出去了
we've all been forced to work in all these years down the block.
你看了多少遍了
How many times have you watched this?
83遍
Eighty-three.
现在84遍了
And now it's 84.
我们很担心成本
We're worried about costs.
所以才来开董事会啊
Well, that's why we call this a "Board meeting."
您妻子来电
让她留言吧
Please take a message.
-汤姆  有很多问题需要考虑  -我知道
- Tom, these are serious concerns. - I know.
-我明白...  -劳拉·布兰德
- Look, I understand... - Lara Brand.
劳拉·布兰德来电
-劳拉·布兰德  -没事  出去接
- Lara Brand. - Oh, no, go ahead. Just take it outside.
伊恩  汤姆在哪里  我联系不上他
Ian, where's Tom? I can't get ahold of him.
他在开董事会  走不开
I can't pry him away from the Board.
各位听我说  我考虑过你们担心的问题
I wanna show you all that I take your concerns very seriously.
我们的运营成本比上个季度高了30%
Our operating costs are up 30% from last quarter.
我最大的担心是
And my first concern is
伊恩为什么开始搞公开募股的事了
why is Ian coming at us with this IPO crap?
他一整天都在开会吗
He's been with the Board all day?
他很难挤出时间
It's hard to get Tom's attention.
也许我应该加入董事会
Maybe I should join the Board.
或者你可以来坐我的位子  真的
Or you can take my job. Please.
伊恩跟我们提过想法
Ian approached us with the idea.
他准备了一份非常诱人的方案
He's put together a very attractive proposal.
公开募股就意味着我们会有一笔大收入
A public offering means a big payday for all of us.
我们已经把好几年的利润投进了那座楼  汤姆
Now, we've sunk years of revenue into that building, Tom.
差不多该回本了
It's time to cash out.
我们有很多现金  不是吗
Come on, we got plenty of cash, don't we?
那是为什么
And why?
因为我们做航空  做连锁超市  做手机
Because we built airlines and retail chains and phone companies,
但是没人会记得
but no one is gonna remember any of those
因为转手太多次
because they keep changing hands.
但是一百年后
But 100 years from now,
大家透过窗子看到那座大楼
when people look out their windows and they see that tower,
能够看到"布兰德"这个名字
they're gonna see the name "Brand"
这将是他们永远不会忘记的名字
and that's a name they will never forget.
而我绝对不愿意卖掉这份财富
And that is not something that I am willing to sell.
企业不是用来帮你作秀的  汤姆
We're not running a charity for your ego, Tom.
好吧  那就来玩个游戏
Okay. Well, then instead, let's play a little game.
就当好玩了
You know, just for the fun of it.
如果公司抬头里有你的名字请举手
Raise your hand if your name is on the company letterhead.
-汤姆  -不  来吧  我们只是投个票
- Tom... - No, no. Come on, we'll just call it a vote.
-汤姆  -51%
- Tom... - Fifty-one percent!
赢了的感觉真好
Feels good to win.
你们可以在我葬礼上卖了我的股份
You can sell shares at my funeral.
下次伊恩想当执行总裁的时候
And the next time Ian wants to play CEO,
我们可以一起炒了他
we can fire him together.
-能借一步说话吗  -现在不行
- Hey, can I borrow you for a minute? - Not now.
关于那座塔
It's about the tower.
我已经跟你爸说了我们的塔高出100英尺
I already talked to your dad about this. We're 100 feet taller.
我知道那是项目规划
I know that's the projection.
但那只是参考
But that's printed to scale.
芝加哥的比我们的高了60英尺
Chicago's beating us by 60.
我漏了什么东西吗  我们的更高才对
Am I missing something here? We're taller.
他们天花板里有很多钢筋
There's too much steel in their roof.
所以呢
So?
所以额定承重760吨
So that's rated for 760 tons,
现在上面什么都没有
and there's nothing on it.
但如果他们这样放钢材
But if they laid that much steel...
他们还没有完成
They're not done.
不  这不在他们的计划内
No, that's not in their plans.
他们知道我们有他们的计划
They know we have their plans.
他们想让我们觉得我们赢了
They want us to think we're winning
但他们已经批准了那个计划
but they got a permit for that
现在他们要比我们高60英尺了
and they are beating us by 60 feet.
大卫
David!
好吧  先保密
Right. Keep this quiet.
伊恩  在马德里那午睡时间之前
Oh, Ian, let's make that call to Madrid
给那边的人打个电话
before they take their siesta.
当然
Absolutely.
你知道  我们是有清洁工的
You know, we do have janitors.
-我一直在忙  -我有东西要给你
- Yeah. I've been busy. - I got you something.
为你成为男子汉而准备的
谢了  爸
Thanks, Dad.
火兰德公司
为你成为男子汉而准备的
很抱歉打扰你吃晚餐  但我需要那份报告
I'm sorry to break up your dinner, but I need that report.
告诉你老婆我来买单
Well, tell your wife the check's on me.
但她明年还是会有周年纪念的
Yeah, but she gets another anniversary next year.
我并不关心
I don't really care.
打扰一下  你看到我妻子了吗
Oh, excuse me, have you seen my wife anywhere?
她长什么样
What does she look like?
她是全世界最美的女人
She is the most beautiful woman in the entire world.
也许我见过她  让我看一看
Oh, well, maybe I have seen her. Let me see.
找到了  是她吗
Oh, here we go. Is this her?
给她打个电话吧
Oh, let's give her a call.
今天很忙  我错过什么了吗
Yeah, it was a busy day. What did I miss?
我生日是上个月
Uh, my birthday was last month.
你在跟我开玩笑吗
You're joking me right now?
你还不如让我去工作
You're gonna have to give me more to work with than that.
-糟糕  不会是今天吧  -明天
- Oh, damn it. It's not today? - Tomorrow.
那就好  我还没错过
Oh, well, then I haven't missed it.
年度父亲
Father of the year.
所以我们买什么送她
So, what did we get her?
我们什么都没买
Oh, we didn't get her anything.
你忙到连说五分钟话的时间都没有
You were too busy to talk for five minutes,
所以我买了一个化妆包
so I got her a makeup kit.
不能说那个化妆包是我们俩送的吗
Oh, well, couldn't we say that the makeup kit's from both of us?
-不能  -好吧
- No. - Fine.
我该给她买点什么
What should I get her?
也许你应该问问她想要什么
Maybe you should ask her what she wants.
趁她还没上大学
Try getting to know her a little bit
试着了解她一下吧
before she heads off to college.
别这样  还有七年呢
Come on. I still got seven years left.
或者是六年  我开玩笑呢
Or, no, six years. I'm kidding.
你就是这样带大卫的吗
Is this how you raised David?
我儿子现在还不错
My son turned out just fine.
他为了见你不得不去你那工作
He had to apply for a job to see his dad.
当然  他母亲有完全监护权
Well, of course. His mother got full custody.
我那个律师太糟糕
I had a terrible lawyer.
你参加丽贝卡的派对的时候
When you come to Rebecca's party...
还有一个月  我们就要建成最高的建筑
Look, we are a month away from opening the tallest building in...
汤姆  你去参加丽贝卡聚会的时候
Tom! When you come to Rebecca's party,
你得到场并且带一份精美的礼物
you gotta be here and you have to bring an exceptional gift.
爸爸
Daddy!
宝贝儿
Hey, baby.
天啊  睡衣真漂亮
Oh, my Goodness. Those are such fancy pajamas.
确实很漂亮
Yeah, aren't they?
-这不是睡衣  -不是吗
- They're not pajamas. - They're not?
但你是不是该睡觉了  她什么时候睡觉
But isn't it your bedtime? What time is her bedtime?
她和我们一起去
She's coming with us.
妈妈说我可以去见梅厄
Mom says I get to meet the Mayor.
真的吗
Really?
真是父女情深的一刻
Quality father-daughter bonding time.
那里会有吃的吗
Will there be food?
一万刀一份
It's $10,000 a plate.
你得像皇后一样优雅的吃饭
You're gonna eat like a queen.
会有披萨吗
Will there be pizza?
有  一万刀的披萨
Yes, $10,000 pizza.
儿童基金在市长的领导下蒸蒸日上
The children's fund has thrived under the Mayor's leadership.
为了保证爱德华兹市长能从中获利
And to make sure Mayor Edwards gets something out of it,
他将把投票年龄下调至十岁
he's gonna lower the voting age to ten.
每个人都会问我为什么我的丈夫
Everyone asks me why my husband
会来组织慈善活动
is hosting a charity event.
因为汤姆很爱孩子
The truth is Tom loves children.
他说他们造出了最好的智能手机
He says they make the best smartphones.
我没听懂
I don't get it.
她刚才呛了你爸
She just burned your dad.
他们说和孩子相处的时光
They say there is no substitute
是无可替代的
for time with your children.
我们知道  在这个房间里  钱更重要
Although, we know, in this room, money comes close.
这也就是为什么这个慈善基金会这么受欢迎
And that's why this charity is so popular.
如果你没有时间陪孩子
If you don't have time for kids,
我们可以把你的钱拿走来减轻你的负罪感
we'll ease your guilt by taking your dough.
这也就是为什么汤姆·布兰德同意
Which is why Tom Brand has agreed to host this benefit
再组织七年慈善活动
for the next seven years.
废话不多说  有请我的丈夫
So without further ado, please welcome my husband,
一个没种的家伙  汤姆·布兰德
a real pussy cat, Tom Brand.
所以  今天是个大日子
So, today is the big day.
你想好要什么了吗
Have you thought about what you want?
我想要一只猫
I want a cat.
我们那栋楼不能带宠物
Oh, I don't think our building takes pets.
可那栋楼是你的呀
You own the building.
等等  你去年是不是也说要一只猫
Wait, didn't you ask for a cat last year?
对  你给我买了一个足球桌
Yeah, and you got me a foosball table.
亲爱的  很多孩子都想要足球桌的
Honey, most kids would kill for a foosball table.
但我的朋友没人玩桌上足球
Yeah, but none of my friends play foosball.
所以至少给我只猫  我可以和猫玩
So, at least if I have a cat, I can play with the cat.
好吧  好吧  我向你保证
All right, all right. I'll make you a deal.
-我会考虑考虑  怎么样  -太好了
- I will think about it. How about that? - Yes!
给她买珠宝  女孩子喜欢珠宝
Get her jewelry. Girls love jewelry.
可以考虑苹果产品
Pull some strings with Apple,
给她弄一个最新iPhone的原型机
get her a prototype of the new iPhone.
私人演唱会怎么样
How about a private concert?
-你知道她喜欢哪个乐队吗  -不知道
- You know what band she is into? - No.
我的建议有点冒犯
I have a radical suggestion.
你有问过丽贝卡她想要什么吗
Have you tried asking Rebecca what she wants?
问过  她想要一只猫
Yes, she wants a cat.
可以  那在你经济范围之内
Well, that's in your price range.
我讨厌猫
I hate cats.
它们满屋子吐  不守规矩
They puke all over the house. They shed all over everything.
我有了一个前妻  一个现任  两个孩子
I got an ex-wife, a wife and two kids,
我不想再养东西了
I don't need another thing to feed.
矮种马怎么样
What about a pony?
你能笑一下吗  这是派对
Could you smile? It's a party.
为什么我们总要来
Why do we always come here?
或多或少  他们是家人
They're family. More or less.
你在叫什么  电梯里又没有松鼠
What are you barking at? There are no squirrels in the elevator.
给你  拉着他
Here, take him.
假装你很享受遛狗
Just pretend you're having fun.
你在逗我吗
Seriously?
生日快乐
Happy birthday!
我特喜欢这个年度盛典
I love this yearly ritual
汤姆不记得丽贝卡生日
where Tom forgets Rebecca's birthdays
你也不记得汤姆不记得丽贝卡生日
and you forget that Tom forgets Rebecca's birthdays.
他偶尔还是能记住的
He kind of remembered.
-你得敲响警钟了  -麦迪逊
- You'd have to fire a warning shot. - Madison!
汤姆和我离婚时  他和一个年轻模特好上了
When Tom and I divorced, he got the younger model.
我都不好意思了
I'm blushing.
如果他再失去你  就会去染指未成年了
If he loses you, it's jailbait.
那还挺浪漫的
Well, that's romantic.
到时候我希望你去找我的律师
I want you to call my lawyer.
你是不是收了中介费
Do you get a finder's fee?
劳拉  我和汤姆离婚那天
Lara, the day Tom and I divorced
简直是我这辈子最快乐的一天
was the happiest day of my life.
我希望你也能拥有这份快乐
I want that happiness for you.
来吧  趁你没醉得拿得不稳东西  来帮帮忙
Come on, help me out before your hands get all shaky.
喝完这杯就走
This is for the road.
我可不想被汤姆看到我们在一起
I don't want Tom catching us together.
他能拿你怎样呢  再跟你离一次婚吗
What's he gonna do? Divorce you again?
要是他能  他自然乐意
He would if he could.
你的生日派对上会有男生来吗
Are there gonna be any boys at the party?
没有
No.
你就要满11岁了  丽贝卡
You're turning 11, Rebecca.
是时候谈恋爱了  我可以帮你
Now's the time. I could help you, you know.
就像我妈帮助你妈那样
Like how my mom helps your mom.
-什么  -没什么
- What? - Never mind.
我喜欢你的房间
I love your room.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我爸爸其实更乐意花时间陪我
My dad actually likes spending time with me,
所以他从不必花钱来补偿我
so he never has to buy me off.
来  要发照片了  笑一个
Come on. Smile for Instagram.
送她只毛绒玩偶猫怎么样
What if you got her a plush cat?
看  名义上算是只猫
See, technically, it's a cat.
不  严格来说  那不是只猫
No, technically, it's not a cat.
芝加哥那边刚刚宣布
Chicago just announced.
等等  有了  我知道了
Hang on. I got it, I got it, I got it.
看看日本的田代岛
Take a look at Tashirojima,
又以"猫岛"著称
also known as Cat Island.
你可以请一位保姆陪她一起去
Put her up there with a nanny.
最重要的是  你都不用亲自去那里
Best part, you don't even have to be there.
这点子不错
That's interesting.
她每年都说想要一只猫
She asks for a cat every single year.
你不能就这样花钱了事
You can't just buy your way out.
布兰德先生  我认为
Mr. Brand, I think the fact that
你让我们花如此多时间精力来讨论这件事
you've had us put so much time and thought into this
本身就足以证明你对她的关心了
is really gonna show her you care.
如果你真的想让她感受到你的诚意
If you wanna show her you really care,
就给她她真正想要的
just get her what she really wants.
一只真正的猫
A cat.
回电
天呐
Jeez.
最近的宠物店距此约2.7公里
Nearest pet shop, 1.7 miles.
伊恩·考克斯
该死的
Damn it.
重新计算路线
Recalculating.
前方160米处右转
In one-tenth of a mile, make a right turn.
此处左转
Make a left turn.
喵金斯宠物店
您已到达目的地
You have arrived.
我的天
Jeez!
离我远点
Get away from me.
闭嘴
Shut up.
有人吗
Hello? Hello?
-你好  -嗨
- Oh, hello. - Hi.
你看起来很眼熟  我们见过吗
You look familiar. Have we met?
我不这么觉得
Oh, I doubt it.
我一定在哪见过你
I know you from somewhere.
好吧  我经常上电视
Well, I'm on TV a lot.
对  《动物星球》  我喜欢这个节目
Yes! Animal Planet. I love that show.
不  不是《动物星球》
No, not Animal Planet.
我是汤姆·布兰德  火兰德的老总
I'm Tom Brand. I own FireBrand.
我想起来了
There you go.
我在猫砂盆里用的是报纸
I use newspaper in the poopy boxes,
铲屎的时候总能看见你的脸
and I see your face all the time.
我还有急事要迟到了
Look, I'm a little late for something,
所以我们能赶紧说重点吗
so if we could just get on with it?
-喵  -当然了
- Meow! - Sure.
你不喜欢猫吧  布兰德先生
You don't like cats, do you, Mr. Brand?
我能直接挑一只走吗  然后我就要上路了
Look, can I just pick one out? And then I'll be on my way.
不是你选猫  而是猫选你
You don't pick a cat. The cat picks you.
听着  我的决定动辄牵涉上百万美元
Look, I make million-dollar decisions for lunch.
我确定我选只猫还是绰绰有余的
I'm pretty sure I can pick out a cat.
看到了吗  它喜欢你
See that? He likes you.
怪不得  它就喜欢困惑不安的灵魂
It figures because he's attracted to troubled souls.
它的九条命已然去了七条
Used up seven lives already.
也就是说芝加哥将坐拥北美最高楼
That'll give Chicago the tallest building in North America
而纽约的火兰德大楼只能退居其次
which leaves New York and FireBrand in second place.
你该选只食盆了
You should pick a bowl.
我们暂未采访到公司相关负责人
The company could not be reached for comment.
但随着一个月后开幕仪式的举行
But with the opening ceremony just a month away...
毛绒裤先生
"毛绒裤先生"
"Mister Fuzzypants."
很好
Yeah. Yeah. Good.
很好的选择
Good choice.
你能直接帮我包上吗
Yeah. Could you just wrap it up for me?
没问题
Sure.
我理解这一点
You know, I get it.
你的公司以你的姓布兰德命名
"Brand" Because your name is Brand.
-但为什么是"火兰德"呢  -多少钱
- But why "Fire"? - How much do I owe you?
因为不巧我也做了同样的事
I ask because I did the same thing, see.
我名为珀金斯
My name is Perkins,
所以我的店名是"喵金斯"
so I call my store "Purrkins."
我懂了
Oh, I see there.
我们真是如出一辙啊
We're just like two peas in a pod.
不用找了
Yeah. Keep the change.
出手大方
Oh, wow.
-你最好不要接  -什么
- You might not wanna take that. - I'm sorry?
你买了礼物  又快迟到了
You're running late, it's a gift.
你不想误了时辰吧
You don't want to be late.
赶去参加派对
For the party?
说的很对
Right.
伊恩  到底怎么回事
Ian, what the hell is going on?
猫咪们
Okay, cats.
我们行动吧
Let's do this.
真棒
Oh, good job.
-宝贝  生日快乐  -谢谢
- Happy birthday, baby. - Thank you.
第一块给我们的小寿星
Okay, first piece for the birthday girl.
给爸爸留一块吧
And save some for Daddy.
放在冰箱里去年留的蛋糕旁边就好
Just put it in the freezer next to last year's slice.
怎么了
What?
在这等着
Wait here.
别吵了
Shut up.
你买了猫送她
Went with the cat.
明智之举
Smart move.
新闻上不是在开玩笑吧
Was that news report a joke?
汤姆  我们还可以扭转局面
Tom, we can turn this around.
回头往上看
Just look up there.
那根天线有14米长
That antenna's 47 feet.
我问了我们的工程师
I spoke to our engineers,
只要装上天线支架就能把它支高
and if we install support lines, we can raise it up.
我们在新世贸大厦就是这么干的
That's what they did at One World Trade.
别说了  你从城市那头把我叫来
Stop. You dragged me across town
又爬了579米高  就为了说这个
and up 1,900 feet to tell me this?
这是解决方案
This is a solution.
-那条天线  -你还跟我说天线
- That antenna is... - Antenna?
我要的是最高楼  伊恩  不是信号最好的楼
I wanted the tallest building, Ian, not the best reception.
也许我们还可以加高楼层
Well, maybe we can add more floors.
你知道我们耗费多少心力
Do you know how much planning went into this?
才获得许可建这么高的楼吗
To get permission to build it this height?
全给你毁了  我们现在只能
You blew it. We're now standing
站在北美第二高楼顶上
on the second tallest building in North America.
只是第二而已  就因为你忙着
Number two, because you were busy
想方设法背着我卖掉我的公司
trying to sell my company behind my back.
-汤姆  -收拾东西给我滚
- Tom... - Pack up your office!
我迟到了  我知道了  不要打了
I'm late. I know. Stop calling.
-拉我上去  -你不是要开除我吗
- Pull me up. - You're firing me?
拉我一把
Take my hand!
好痛
That hurt.
血压稳定
BP holding steady.
好  我数三下  抬起来
Okay, let's do this on three.
准备好了吗
Ready?
一  二  三
One, two, three.
那家伙呢
What about that guy?
这小家伙状况还不错
Huh, this little guy looks fine.
那个人看起来比我糟糕多了
Wow, that guy looks worse off than me.
他穿着我的衣服
And he's wearing my clothes.
那是我的腰带
And that's my belt.
不是吧
Seriously?
这只是一场噩梦
It's just a bad dream!
好消息是你丈夫撑过来了
The good news is your husband made it
没有术后并发症
through surgery with no complications,
但是他脑部严重受创  失去意识
but he had severe head trauma and is unresponsive.
我这是失去意识
You call this unresponsive?
什么时候他能醒过来
When will he wake up?
布兰德太太  你丈夫在昏迷之中
Mrs. Brand, your husband's in a coma.
等过段日子
Once the swelling in the
他脑部的肿胀消除以后
brain is reduced over the next couple of days,
他的状况可能就会好转
that's when we're more likely to see a recovery.
但是现在  他的意识还没有恢复
But right now, he's not in there.
因为我的意识在这里
That's because I'm in here!
劳拉  听我说  我在这儿
Lara, listen to me! It's me!
谢天谢地  你能听见我
Thank God. You can hear me.
等一下  等等  等等  等等
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
不  不  不  不
No, no, no, no.
不要把我拿出去
Don't leave me back there.
把我和我的身体放在一起
Hey, leave me with me.
宝贝
Hi, baby.
我能看看爸爸吗
Can I see Daddy?
他在睡觉  还不能和我们讲话
Well, he is sleeping right now so he can't talk to us,
不过  他可能能听到我们
but maybe he can hear us.
我们一起进去  好吗
We'll go in together, okay?
-来吧  -我们能看他吗
- Come on. - Shall we see?
这太耻辱了
Oh, this is so humiliating.
劳拉  我想要拉他上来的
Hey, Lara. I tried to lift him up,
但是我不够强壮
but I wasn't strong enough.
-犹大  -那不是你的错
- Judas. - No, it's not your fault.
那只猫是谁的
Whose cat is that?
我想它是你的
I think he's yours.
应该是你爸爸买的  我们去看看他
I think your dad got him. Let's go see.
爸爸给我买了一只猫
Daddy got me a cat?
不可思议  对吧
Amazing, isn't it?
我说过我会打电话的
I said I'd call.
那个谁  谁都行
Hello, someone, anyone.
我被困在猫的身体里
I'm trapped inside a cat's body.
谁来救救我
Somebody help me!
你  那个穿难看绿夹克的
You, in the horrible green jacket.
你好吗
So, how are you doin' in there?
噩梦还在继续
The nightmare continues.
布兰德先生  这不是梦
Mr. Brand, this is no dream.
您能听见我
You can hear me? - Shh.
我是个猫语者
I'm a cat whisperer.
我是唯一能听懂你的话的人
And I'm the only one who can hear you.
你对我做了什么
What did you do to me?
我什么也没做  你从屋顶上摔下来了
I didn't do anything. You fell off a roof.
好吧  我要怎么从它身上出去
Fine. How do I get out of this?
错误的问题
Wrong question.
你应该问问  我是怎么进入到它身体里的
You should ask, "How did I get into this?"
好吧  我是怎么进入到它身体里的
Fine! How did I get into this?
继续问这个问题
Keep asking that question.
我希望你能自己找出答案
I hope you figure it out.
什么意思
What does that mean?
你的身体不能撑太久
Your body won't last long.
如果你不能及时回去  你接下来的一生
If it expires, you're gonna be stuck in there
就会被一直困在这只猫的身体里
for the rest of your life.
把我从这里面弄出来  你这个婊子养...
You get me out of here, you son of a...
冷静  布兰德先生
Calm down, Mr. Brand.
你是一只猫
You're a cat.
这不是世界末日
It's not the end of the world.
我讨厌猫
I hate cats.
所以才如此完美了
That's what makes this so perfect.
好吧
All right.
冷静
Calm down.
我以为爸爸会送给我一只小奶猫
I thought Daddy would get me a kitten.
它有点脏兮兮
He is scruffy, isn't he?
你要换一只吗
What, you want to trade him in.
不
No!
我也觉得你不会
I didn't think so.
欢迎到家  猫咪
All right, welcome home, cat.
可能我们应该让它自在点
Maybe we should let him get comfortable.
它想要探索新家
He wants to explore.
我今晚可以和你一起睡吗  妈妈
Can I sleep with you tonight, Mommy?
好  孩子
Yeah, kiddo.
你陪陪我也挺好
I could use the company.
留言  让她们知道这只猫就是我
Message. Let them know I'm me.
留个言
Write a message.
简单
Simple.
我是汤姆
"Oh, hi, it's Tom.
救我出来
"Get me out of here."
只需要几个单词
Just need a few words.
没什么难的
Nothing complicated.
亲爱的劳拉  不要惊慌  我是汤姆
Dear Lara, don't panic. It's Tom.
我被困在一只猫的身体里了
I seem to be trapped in the body of a cat.
这不是开玩笑
This is not a joke.
你亲爱的老公  汤姆
Your loving husband, Tom.
好吧  这样不行
Okay, that didn't work.
不过  对于一只猫来说已经不错了
Although, not bad for a cat.
讽刺的是  我现在真想玩鼠标
Ironically, I could really use a mouse right now.
妈妈  爸爸什么时候回家
Mommy, when is Daddy gonna come home?
他一醒过来  就会回来
Just as soon as he wakes up.
他们应该用一个大闹钟闹醒他
They should use a really big alarm clock.
你将来会成为一个好医生的
You'd be a great doctor.
你想要什么  猫咪
What do you want, kitty?
钱夹  加上  身份证  等于
Money clip, plus license equals...
我被困在猫里
I'm stuck in a cat!
它想要和我们一起玩
He wants to play.
抱歉  猫咪  我们要睡了
Well, sorry, kitty. It is bedtime in here.
我们明天可以一起玩
But we can play tomorrow.
明天
Tomorrow?
好吧
Okay.
我们刚才说到哪儿了
Where were we?
如果我在猫的身体里
If I'm in a cat's body,
那只猫在我身体里吗
is a cat in my body?
我一直都讨厌这块地毯
I always hated that rug.
这个苏格兰威士忌后劲真不赖
This is good scotch.
昨晚很难熬
Rough night?
没有  我只是在沉思
No. I was just contemplating
如何以猫的身体度过余生
the rest of my life as a cat.
好吧
Okay.
天哪
Jesus!
你饿了吗
Who's hungry?
很好吃哦
Yum yum.
我看了就饱了
Looks like a cat already ate this.
祝你有个好胃口
Bon appetit.
法国人  他们就会卖这些东西
French. That'll sell this stuff.
好了
All right.
这是你的猫厕所
There's your litter box.
不用了  我有那块地毯了
No, thank you, I have the rug.
留给爸爸
我当时有事才没来的
I had a really good excuse.
现在她泪闸要开了
Here come the floodgates.
你可能觉得我为了一块蛋糕就哭  好像疯了
You probably think I'm crazy crying over a piece of cake.
也可能是为了你的丈夫还在医院里昏迷
Or that your husband's in the hospital in a coma.
他会醒过来的
He's gonna wake up.
对吧
Right?
我一定要去找那个叫珀金斯的
Oh, I really gotta find that Perkins guy.
宿醉中
Hangover!
你好  猫咪
Hello, kitty.
我们该叫你什么名字
What should we call you?
这是你的名字吗  毛绒裤先生
Is that your name? Mister Fuzzypants?
可恨的因果报应
I hate karma.
你是我得到过最棒的礼物
You're the best gift I ever got.
不  太贴心了
No, too sweet.
一点也不好笑
That wasn't funny.
那你们俩在笑什么
What are you two laughing at?
我没觉得好笑
I don't think it's funny.
明白吗  这就是我的观点
See, this is my point of view.
我们不需要增加高度  而是要使用一些策略
We don't need high rises, we need strategic growth.
我们说的就是这个意思
And that's what we've all been saying.
我们现在根本不应该讨论这些
We shouldn't even be talking about this now.
我们面对的并非危机
This isn't a crisis.
而是机遇
This is an opportunity.
怎么了
What?
你想要什么
What do you need?
我不是我
我是人
想吃东西的话  去猫食盆里找
If you want food, it's in the bowl.
是吃果味麦片
Fruity Pebbles
还是吃那个
or that?
就吃果味麦片
Fruity Pebbles.
我是猫  我是猫  我是猫  我是猫
Be the cat, be the cat, be the cat, be the cat, be the cat!
很优雅
Graceful.
是吗  你来试试
Yeah? You try it.
成功登陆
And, nailed it!
我也打电话给你妈妈了
I called your mom, too.
我只是希望把大家聚在一起
I just wanted to get everyone together.
味道真诱人
Well, it smells great.
你在做什么吃的
What are you cooking?
烤全猫
Roast cat.
估计它的脑袋刚才摔坏了
Maybe its head got screwed up in the fall.
它是个酒鬼  不肯吃东西
He's an alcoholic. I can't get him to eat,
可我却发现装着五十年麦卡伦的
but I found an empty decanter,
酒瓶空空如也  上面沾满了猫毛
of 50-year-old Macallan with fur all over it.
至少它品味还不错
Well, at least he has good taste.
也许我应该在它的食物里掺点苏格兰威士忌
Maybe I should mix scotch into his food.
我能用一下爸爸的办公室吗
Can I use Dad's office for a bit?
当然  怎么了
Yeah, what's up?
我想看看我还能做些什么
I just want to see if I can find anything else
来扭转这整个芝加哥的...
that might help me with this whole Chicago...
猫可以做核磁共振吗
Do they make MRIs for cats?
你是指CAT扫描[层状扫描]吗
You mean CAT scans?
我掉在刀上就好了
I should have landed on the knives.
我去办公室了
I'll be in the office.
你好
Hi.
难道
So,
你现在跟爸爸一样了吗
are you like Dad now?
你想说什么
What do you mean?
你成为公司的总裁了吗
Are you president of the company?
不  我的工作没变化  只是没有爸爸在了
No, I'm doing the same job, just without Dad.
你过会儿能出来吗
Can you come out soon?
可以  马上就来
Yeah, in a minute.
你真是像极了爸爸
You're so totally like Dad.
劳拉
Lara!
这下可好  "撒旦"过来吃晚饭了
Oh, good! Satan's over for dinner.
汤姆的事我很抱歉
So sorry about Tom.
我一直以为他会因为跳伞出事
I always thought it would be skydiving,
或者他的秘书会带着
or that his secretary would just snap
一支乌兹冲锋枪冲到办公室
and bring an Uzi to the office.
我还觉得你会因肉毒素过量而死呢
I thought you'd die from a Botox overdose.
你把狗带来了
Oh, you brought the dogs.
公主  珍妮特
Princess, Jeanette!
你知道汤姆昏迷了吧  你可以休息一个晚上
You know Tom's unconscious, right? You can take the night off.
是啊  可总得有人继续干活啊
Yeah, well, someone has to keep things going.
我永远搞不懂你为什么要为他工作
I never understood why you wanted to work for him anyway.
妈  你能不和我说话...
Mom, if we could not talk...
喝这个可不健康
This isn't healthy.
治疗悲伤的心灵鸡汤
Chicken soup for grief.
别追了  走开
Stop it. Get out of here.
坐下
Heel!
你能把它们带走吗  它们吓到它了
Can you please take them away? They're really scaring him.
它们对其他动物特别敏感
They have a very strong sense about other animals.
-你爸爸从哪里把它弄来的  -怎么了
- Where'd your dad get him? - Why?
他不会是从大街上捡回来的吧
Well, did he just pick him up off the streets?
它只是毛有些乱而已
He's just a little messy.
我知道你不开心  因为你爸爸快死了
I know you're upset because your dad's dying...
他不会死的  他只是昏迷
He's not dying. He's just unconscious.
我妈妈说了  你妈妈
My mom says your mom
应该客观面对他的情况
should be more realistic about his condition.
公主  珍妮特  坐下
Princess, Jeanette, heel!
T
O
M
M.
汤姆
Tom
麦迪逊  大卫  丽贝卡  妮可
Madison, David, Rebecca, Nicole.
什么
What?
我给汤姆留了个位子
I set a place for Tom.
这可是个怪异的习惯
Well, that's a weird habit.
他应该通常不在家吃晚饭吧
It's not like he's usually here for dinner.
麦迪逊  别在今晚说这些
Madison, not tonight.
就算他在  我也是这么说
I'd say the same thing if he were here.
是啊  所以没有人喜欢你
Yes, that's why nobody likes you.
但你一直去找乔什总是有原因的
But there's a reason you've been seeing Josh.
乔什
Josh?
我现在可不愿想那事
Oh, I can't even think about that right now.
现在正是大好时机  汤姆不可能发现了
Now's the perfect time. It's not like Tom could catch you.
谁还需要猫砂盆吗
Who needs a litter box?
麦迪逊  我是一只坏坏猫
Oh, Madison? I've been a bad kitty.
你...
Hey! You...
停下来
Cheese!
真是抱歉
Sorry, everybody.
-等等  -怎么了
- Wait. - What?
没什么  我还以为我看到了...没事
Nothing, I just thought I saw... Nothing. It's okay.
劳拉  快把那只猫杀了
Lara, that cat needs to be put down.
我给你买个新包  麦迪逊
I'll buy you a new bag, Madison.
找个训猫师  或者猫语者什么的  我不管
Hire a trainer, a cat whisperer, I don't care.
我来给你开瓶新的马丁尼酒
Let's get you a new martini.
好的
Yes.
总得有人说说这空椅子的事吧
Well, someone's gotta talk about the empty chair.
我们是不是该说段祝酒词
Should we do toasts?
这又不是守灵  妈
It's not a wake, Mom.
这不是汤姆第一次进医院了
This isn't Tom's first time in the hospital.
还记得他成立航空公司那会儿吗
Remember when he launched the airline?
他总是在打电话  不眠不休
He was always on the phone, never slept.
还记得你问我什么
You know what you asked me?
吸血鬼
Vampire.
为什么爸爸是个吸血鬼
Why is Daddy a vampire?
因为妈妈把他的血吸干了
Because Mommy sucked all his blood.
他通宵达旦地工作
He'd stay awake all night working out,
然后有一天  他在跑步机上跑步时就睡着了
and then one day, he just fell asleep on a moving treadmill.
他在医院呆了一周
He was in the hospital for a week.
那是我最棒的假期
Best vacation I ever had.
有时我在凌晨四点醒来  发现他在阳台上
I'd wake up and find him on the balcony at 4:00 A.M.
呆呆地望着他的大厦
just staring at his tower.
我得为汤姆说句话
I'll say this for Tom.
他从来没有其他女人
There was never another woman.
和我在一起时  是航空公司
With me, it was an airline.
和你在一起时  是摩天大厦
With you, it's a big skyscraper.
今晚听到的话都别当真
Ignore everything you hear tonight.
别拿我做榜样  丽贝卡
I'm not a role model, Rebecca.
你已经习惯了
You're used to it.
说段祝酒词吧
How about that toast?
-祝爸爸早日醒过来  -我们想念你
- To Dad. Wake up soon. - We miss you.
或者说你的大厦想念你
Or your tower misses you.
睡得好吗
Sleep well?
丽贝卡·艾莉森·布兰德
Rebecca Alison Brand,
你的猫把黄页给毁了
your cat destroyed the yellow pages!
黄页是什么
What's a yellow pages?
喵金斯宠物店
出售宠物
食物和用品
猫咪寄放
行为训练
咨询
你买的那只猫
That cat you got,
幸亏你这会儿在医院里
he's lucky you're in here
不然你已经把它给宰了
or you'd have killed him by now.
我有个计划可以击败芝加哥
I got a plan to beat Chicago.
就等董事会接受这个计划了
I just need to sell it to the Board.
等你醒过来  我们可能已经成为第一名了
When you wake up, we might be number one.
我们一定会尽力的
We're doing the best that we can do.
好  非常感谢
Okay. Thank you so much.
你在这儿干什么
What are you doing here?
我的手腕扭了  所以才拉不住你爸爸
Sprained my wrist. That's why I couldn't hold on to your Dad.
你来找我爸的神经科医生看手腕
You're seeing my Dad's neurologist about your wrist?
董事会需要他最新的身体状况
The Board needs updates on his status.
那问我啊
So ask me.
我们不会从悲痛丧父的人那里听取医疗建议的
We're not going to take medical advice from the grieving son.
现在是公司的巨大转型
It's a massive transition for the company.
什么转型
What transition?
办公室的大日子  祝你与董事会沟通顺利
Big day at the office. Good luck with the Board.
我们差了那么多
We're losing by that much.
再多20米  我们就第一了
We get 70 feet, we're number one.
我们现在的结构不能支撑再多一层
Now, our structure can't support another floor,
可惜我们也不能
and unfortunately we can't
偷运一个大铁锤进芝加哥
just smuggle a wrecking ball into Chicago,
所以我们需要减重
so we need to shed weight.
我还以为我们要建高一些
I thought we were making it taller.
我们拆掉一层
We lose one floor,
能换来这个
it buys us this.
那会塌的
That's gonna collapse.
用钛合金就不会
Not if we use titanium.
怎么不用黄金呢
Why don't we just build it out of gold?
它和钢一样硬  但重量只有一半
It's as strong as steel and half the weight.
我不知道你在解决什么问题
I don't know what problem you're trying to solve here.
什么意思
Excuse me?
这里是曼哈顿的核心地产
This is a stack of prime real estate in Manhattan.
一个金字塔攀爬顶可收不了租金
We can't charge rent on a jungle gym.
我父亲建造北半球最高的楼
My father didn't build the tallest skyscraper
不是为了一点点租金
in the Northern Hemisphere for a little rent money.
它不是最高的楼
It's not the tallest skyscraper.
因为你搞砸了
Because you screwed up.
听着  如果汤姆在这里
Look. If Tom were here,
你知道他绝对会这么做
you know this is exactly what he would do.
我很钦佩你如此尊重你父亲的想法  大卫
I appreciate that you want to honor your father, David.
我们得注意账目
We need to watch the books.
公司不能总是把钱花在汤姆的玩乐项目上
Our company can't keep diverting funds into Tom's pet projects.
这是他的公司
It's his company.
谢谢你  大卫
Thank you, David.
他还没死
He's not dead.
你想试试吗
You wanna try?
老天救救我吧
Lord help me.
我们来试试  包包不是垃圾箱
Okay, let's try "A purse is not a litter box."
包包不是垃圾箱
A purse is not a litter box.
毛绒裤先生是她父亲给她的最后一样东西
Mr. Fuzzypants was the last thing her father gave her,
所以她很粘着它
so she's really latched on.
它想博得注意  看得出来
Mmm. He wants attention, obviously.
-这是我们的女儿  丽贝卡  -你好
- This is our daughter, Rebecca. - Hello.
你得把我说的每句话都讲给他们听
You are going to tell them every word I say.
摔得漂亮  不错
Good move. Nice.
你倒来试试
You try it.
你爸爸从我的店里买了这只猫  你知道吗
Your dad bought this cat at my store. Did you know that?
谁在乎  帮我翻译
Who cares? Just translate.
我记得他说
I remember, he said
他想把你说想要的给到你
he wanted you to have exactly what you asked for.
猫痴  我不是让你过来无视我的
Hey, cat freak, I didn't call you down here to ignore me.
能让我们单独待会儿吗
Could we have a moment of privacy, please?
你和猫
You and the cat?
-是的  -好吧
- Yeah. - Okay.
你没时间玩游戏了  布兰德先生
You don't have time for games, Mr. Brand.
告诉他们我是谁
Tell them who I am.
我不是你的新闻发布人
I'm not your press agent.
你是个猫语者
Well, you're a cat whisperer,
我挺能肯定我还是只猫
and I'm pretty sure I'm still a cat!
你有没问过自己
Have you asked yourself
你怎么落到这个地步的
how you got into this position?
我试过上网搜  但你知道
I tried googling it, but you know,
没有给猫爪子用的键盘
they don't make keyboards for paws!
你像个野兽一样  快把你家人逼疯了
You're acting like a beast and you're driving your family crazy.
医生没法一直维持你肉体的状况
These doctors can't keep you alive forever,
如果你想要摆脱这个局面  就得乖乖的
so if you want to get out of this, you have to behave.
如果你的肉身死了  就习惯你的爪子吧
And if your human body goes, get used to those paws.
你永远都会是只猫
You'll be a cat forever.
我不要吃猫粮
I am not eating cat food.
你除了猫粮没得选
You'll eat cat food or else.
我重9斤  全身是毛
Oh, I'm 10 pounds and covered in fur.
你还能对我干吗
What else could you possibly do to me?
这只猫没做过手术
This cat has not been fixed.
你敢
Don't you dare.
我应该带他去看兽医吗
Oh, should I take him to the vet?
-珀金斯  -等等吧
- Perkins... - Let's wait.
-如果你敢碰老子一下  -他有些进步了
- ...if you so much as lay a finger on... - He's made progress.
他现在会慢慢进步的
He's gonna be better now.
如果他不吃猫粮  不用猫砂
If he's not eating his food, using his poopy box,
打个电话给我  我亲手给他做
give me a call. I'll clip him myself.
听见没  毛绒裤
You hear that, Fuzzypants?
我是曼哈顿排名第六的富豪
I am the sixth richest person in Manhattan!
一只乖乖的宠物
A well-behaved pet
会给一个家带来爱和舒心
brings love and comfort to a home.
你的家人现在需要这些
And your family needs that right now,
你到底乖不乖
so are you gonna behave?
你得做只猫
You need to be a cat.
好啦  我会做只猫的
Okay, I'll be a cat.
乖乖的
Behave.
不结扎了
No clipping.
先走了
All the best.
慢走
谁要做手术
Who needs to be fixed?
是啊  让三文鱼呼吸一整天气味更浓郁
Yes, letting salmon breathe all day really brings out the flavor.
老天救救我吧
Lord, help me.
猫怎么吃得进这东西
How do cats eat this stuff?
我做不到
Ah... I can't.
饿死了
I'm starving.
加油  毛绒裤  你能行的  加油
Come on. Come on, Fuzzypants, you can do it. Come on.
停住  别动
Hold it, hold it still.
停着别动  别动  别动
Hold it still, hold it, hold it still.
这应该很好玩的吗
Is this supposed to be fun?
真好
Yeah.
直接淹死我吧
Just drown me.
漂亮多了
Well, that's an improvement.
看
Look.
有意思吗
Seriously?
好猫猫
Good kitty.
当众羞辱
Public humiliation.
你好  乔什
Hi, Josh.
乔什
Josh?
我有些东西一定要给你看
I got something I have to show you.
我不能再做下去了
Look, I can't keep doing this.
不  我不接受拒绝  我已经在路上了
No, I'm not taking no for an answer. I'm already on my way.
我不会
Yeah, I'm not gonna...
我把位置发你  好吧
I'll text you the address, okay?
想都别想
Don't even think about it.
来吧  出来  我要走了
Come on, get out of there. I gotta get going.
出来吧
Let's go.
有什么不见了吗
Missing something?
过来  咪咪  过来  咪咪
Here, kitty. Here, kitty. Here, kitty. Here, kitty.
咪咪  咪咪
Kitty, kitty, kitty, kitty.
对不起  亲爱的
Sorry, honey.
咪咪  过来  咪咪
Kitty, kitty. Come on, kitty, kitty.
全世界这么多猫
Of all the cats in the world,
汤姆肯定挑中你  你简直和他一样
of course Tom picked you. You're just like him.
这就是我想告诉你的
That's what I've been trying to tell you.
固执  自私  脱毛
Stubborn and selfish and shedding.
但差别在于
But here's the difference.
法律上规定我不能阉了我的丈夫
I'm legally barred from castrating my husband.
放下
Drop 'em.
好猫猫
Good kitty.
完美
Nailed it!
抱歉  你是谁
Excuse me, who are you?
你又是谁
Who are you?
不关你的事
None of your business.
我们只在俄亥俄州待一天  所以
We've only got one day in Ohio, so...
-你在卖公司  -我等下给你回电话
- You're selling the company. - I'll call you back.
裁切宣传册  排队进行路演
You're cutting the books, you're lining up a roadshow,
还把高盛的人弄来驻扎在会议室
and you got Goldman Sachs camped out in the conference room.
我们要让火兰德上市
We're taking FireBrand public.
在首席执行官昏迷的情况下吗
With the CEO in a coma?
他痊愈的几率
The odds that he recovers...
-等他醒来  -如果能醒
- When he wakes up... - If.
他会把你们全炒掉
He is gonna fire every single one of you.
这是预估内的风险
Calculated risk.
大卫  交易完成之时
David, when this deal goes through,
你们家族会获益数十亿美元
your family makes billions.
就拿着这笔钱吧  你并不欠汤姆·布兰德什么
Just take the money. You don't owe Tom Brand a thing.
乔什
Hi, Josh.
这里真美
This is pretty.
美极了  对吗
It's gorgeous, right?
他是个阿伯克龙比的模特吗
He's an Abercrombie model?
等你看了这景色再赞叹不迟
Wait till you see this view.
-嗨  乔什  -嗨
- Hi, Josh. - Hi.
我们得谈谈
We need to talk.
进屋谈吧
Let's talk inside.
不  就在外面说
No, let's just do it out here.
在哪  草坪上吗
Where, in the grass?
我知道我们已经干了好几个月
I know that we've been at this for months,
你一定很想让我快点做出决定
and you must be anxious for some kind of decision.
我不能一直来见你
I can't keep seeing you.
劳拉  就看一眼
Lara, just take a look at...
毛绒裤先生
Mr. Fuzzypants?
搞什么
Seriously?
你来这里做什么
What are you doing here?
你知道吗  远离城市对于宠物来说真的很棒
You know, getting out of the city is really great for a pet.
而这地方今天刚刚挂牌上市
And this place just went on the market today.
-上市  -我不能再看更多房子了
- Market? - I can't look at any more houses.
什么
What?
待售
乔什·伯恩
房产商
麦迪逊介绍我们认识的时候
When Madison introduced us,
她说你准备好买了
she said you were ready to buy.
我本以为我准备好了
I thought I was.
新房子  新工作  我本准备好要离开汤姆了
New house, new job, I was ready to leave Tom.
她原本要离开我
She was leaving me.
那发生什么改变了呢
So, what's changed?
改变的是我现在有了这个毛蓬蓬的小东西
Well, what's changed is I have this shaggy gremlin,
即使是在他跟踪我的时候
and even when he's stalking me,
他也在不断提醒着我
he's a constant reminder,
汤姆所做的最后一件事是为了他女儿
the last thing Tom did was for his daughter,
还有我爱他
and I love him.
我也爱你
And I love you.
-我得走了  -我从未停止爱你
- I need to go. - I never stopped.
你现在开心了吗
Are you happy now?
除非你也开心
Not until you are.
科尔医生
Dr. Cole.
是坏消息吗
Bad news?
丽贝卡  我刚去看了下你爸爸
Rebecca, I was just visiting Daddy.
他还睡着
He is still sleeping.
但他在逐渐好起来  对吗
He's getting better, though, right?
当他们醒不过来时该怎么办
他的身体正在好转
His body is getting better,
但他昏睡了这么久
but he's been sleeping so long,
科尔医生不知道他还会不会醒
Dr. Cole doesn't know if he's gonna wake up.
但他会醒的
But he could.
他会醒的
He could.
妈妈  那就没事的
Mom, then it's gonna be okay.
爸爸工作那么辛苦  他只是需要多睡会
Dad's been working so hard, he just needs extra sleep.
三只酷猫
Three cool cats
在停在街角的一辆破旧汽车里
Parked on the corner in a beat-up car
分食一根五美分的糖果棒
Dividing up a nickel candy bar
谈论着他们有多聪明
Talking all about how sharp they are
这三只酷猫
These three cool cats
我很抱歉  宝贝
I'm so sorry, baby.
现在别捣乱
Not now.
三位酷酷的小姐姐
Three cool chicks
扭着屁股走在大街上
walkin' down the street Swingin' their hips
分食着一袋薯片
Splitting up a bag of potato chips
而三只酷猫为三位酷酷的小姐姐做了
And three cool cats did three big flips for
三个大大的后空翻
three cool chicks.
第一只酷猫说"老兄  瞧瞧看"
Up popped the first cool cat he said, "Man, look at that!
"老兄  你看到我看到的了吗"
"Man, do you see what I see?"
"我想要中间那个小姐姐"
"I want that middle chick!"
"我想要那个年轻的小姐姐"
"I want that little chick!"
"哥们  给我留个小姐姐"
"Hey, man, save one chick for me!"
三位酷酷的小姐姐
Three cool chicks
她们就像天使
They look like angels from up above
而这三只酷猫真的爱上了她们
And three cool cats really fell in love
但三位酷酷的小姐姐让它们出了洋相
But three cool chicks made three fools of these
三只酷猫
Three cool cats
爱你的爸爸
怎么了
What?
三只酷猫
Three cool cats
怎么了
What's wrong?
爱你的爸爸
天啊
Oh, boy.
我真是个傻瓜
I'm an idiot.
我应该当一位更好的爸爸
I should have been a better dad.
我妈妈说你现在需要人陪
My mom said you needed company right now,
所以我就自告奋勇来了
so I'm volunteering my time.
我现在有点想一个人待着
I kind of wanna be alone right now.
你该去洗一下脸
You should go wash your face.
哭鼻子真的不适合你的肤色
Crying really doesn't work with your complexion.
她真是一团糟
She's a wreck.
你的蠢猫拿了我的
Your stupid cat took my...
你为什么要分享这个
Why would you share this?
我想给男孩子们看看
I wanted to show some boys.
如果他们看见你这么脆弱
If they see you when you're vulnerable,
他们会想要照顾你以及
they'll wanna take care of you and...
你把这照片发给了半个班的人看
You sent this one to half our class.
只是个玩笑而已
That was a joke.
你知道吗  我爸爸现在在医院里昏迷不醒
You know what, my dad is in the hospital.
你解释给我听这算什么玩笑
Explain the joke to me.
我只是想帮帮忙
I was just trying to help.
朋友间就该这么做
That's what friends do.
你知道吗  我妈妈和你妈妈是朋友
You know what, my mom is friends with your mom,
我经常看你过来
and I see you over here a lot,
但别装了  妮可
but stop pretending, Nicole.
我们不是朋友
We're not friends!
我简直无法相信你会这么做
I can't believe you just did that!
干得好  但你为什么会去拿她的手机
Good work, but why did you grab her phone?
因为我是你爸爸
Because I'm your daddy.
利梵托  中等研磨  苦味与醇度兼具
Livanto, round and balanced.
我现在不能玩  毛绒裤先生
I can't play, Mr. Fuzzypants.
那还真是正确答案
That was the right answer.
如果只有这样才能重新变成人
If this is what it takes to become human,
那我要成为这世上最好的猫
I will be the best cat that ever lived.
我给你带了点会让你醒来的东西
Hey, I brought something that's gonna wake you up.
一张参加北半球
An invitation to the grand opening
最高避雷针
of the tallest lightning rod
开幕式的邀请函
in the Northern Hemisphere.
我怀念跟你分享事情  汤姆
I miss sharing things with you, Tom.
所以你得醒过来
That's why you need to wake up.
我是不会孤身一人去参加这个开幕式的
I'm not going to this thing without a date.
火兰德管理层谣言四起
你想出解决办法了吗
Are you figuring this out?
我想再看一下爸爸的那些文件
Hey. I just want another look at Dad's files.
好的
Okay.
一切都还好吗
Is everything all right?
他们今天早上选定了投资者
They locked up investors this morning.
火兰德要在纽交所上市了
FireBrand's going to the New York Stock Exchange.
什么时候
When?
他们会在塔楼开幕的时候宣布
They're announcing it when they open the tower.
伊恩完全瞒着我们
Ian totally went behind our back.
他联合了本森和施泰因以及董事会的其他成员
He's lined up Benson and Stein and the rest of the Board
签订了一项秘密交易协定
in a secret deal.
看来伊恩已经谋划这个计划好几个月了
Turns out, Ian's been working on this plan for months
而且一直在等待适当的时机
and was waiting for the right time.
汤姆会杀了他们的
Tom would kill them.
他们不在乎
They don't care.
他有留下什么书面指示吗
Did he leave any directives or anything?
有份遗嘱  可他还活着啊
Uh, there's a will, but he's not dead.
我知道  我知道
Yeah, I know, I know. I know.
我只是希望能有个凭证
I just hope there's something in here
帮我赢下这场仗
that'll help me fight this thing.
该死  到处都是我
Damn. I'm everywhere.
百丽宫大厦  火兰德大楼
加塔尖  加高楼顶
大卫·布兰德
David Brand.
得给你加薪了
You're gonna need a raise.
不过  还是先给你升个职
But first, let's give you a promotion.
大卫正收集资料  打算采取法律手段
David's pulling files from legal.
他肯定会拼尽全力
He's gonna fight this.
但只要我们投入市场  他就无力回天了
As long as we get to market, he can't do anything.
公司章程  在哪里
Articles of incorporation. Where are they?
我在汤姆的办公桌抽屉里发现了这个
I did find this in Tom's desk.
他把所有的投票股权都留给了大卫
He left all his voting shares to David.
审计部门发现这类文件了吗
Did the audit find anything like this?
当然没有
No.
大卫知道  他肯定知道
David knows. He has to know.
如果他知道  我们早就被赶走了
If he knew, we wouldn't be here.
我从未见过汤姆拥抱大卫
I never saw Tom hug David.
我不太喜欢拥抱
I'm not much of a hugger.
他让大卫在那个杂物间里办公
He's got him working out of that broom closet.
我总是忍不住想叫儿童服务中心来
I keep wanting to call Child Services.
那么
Well then,
我从没见过这个  你呢
I never saw this. Did you?
从来没有
Never.
大家都很欣赏你处理棘手问题的方式
We all appreciate the way you've handled this situation.
公司章程
如果汤姆没挺过来  我们希望你来主持大局
If Tom doesn't pull through, we want you to take the helm.
好  谢谢
Okay, thank you.
坚持住  宝贝儿
-坚持住  -好
- Hang in there. - Yeah.
妈
Hey, Mom.
我把市值数十亿的公司交给你
I hand you the keys to a multi-billion dollar company
你却打电话给你妈
and you call your mother?
你们离婚时拿到的文件都还留着吗
Do you still have the files from the divorce?
聪明
Oh, yeah.
公主  珍妮特  闭嘴
Princess, Jeanette, shut it!
公司头十年的所有档案全在这里了
All of the company records for the first 10 years are in here.
本来应该扔掉的
Should probably get rid of this stuff,
但它们让我怀念往事
but it makes me nostalgic.
-怀念爸爸吗  -他的钱
- For Dad? - His money.
至少你得到了一半
Well, at least you got half.
我不知道他怎么做到的
I don't know how he did it,
白手起家建立这家公司
building this company from scratch.
他从不回家  就是这么做到的
He never came home. That's how he did it.
你做这些干吗
Why are you doing this?
等着他表扬你"干得好"吗
Are you waiting for him to say, "Good job"?
因为你爸是绝不会说这话的
'Cause your father is never gonna give you that.
这是什么
What's this?
火兰德
什么
What?
你爸的公司刚成立那会儿
When your father was just starting off,
他不知道该起什么名字
he couldn't think of a name for the company,
然后突然有一天  你给他画了一幅画
and then one day, you drew a picture of him.
他极少陪你  但他是爱你的
He was never there, but he loved you.
公司章程
这也是你的公司
It's your company, too.
你给这地方起的名字
You named the damn thing.
一家公司对一个病人如此关心实属罕见
It's rare for a company to be so interested in a patient.
汤姆不仅仅是老板  他还是朋友
Tom wasn't just a boss, he was a friend.
我想知道他怎么样了
I want to know how he's doing.
他可能明天就会醒来  也可能永远沉睡
He could wake up tomorrow, he could stay like this forever.
我们无从知晓
We really don't know.
-那概率有多大呢  -很难说
- Well, what are the odds? - It's hard to say.
就目前而言  小于1%
At this point, less than 1%?
如果你已经做过功课了
If you've done your research,
我不知道你还想知道什么
I don't know what else you want.
我担心你给了他妻子错误的希望
I'm concerned that you're giving his wife false hope.
我告诉她了我们不能确定
I told her we don't know.
你知道  这么说会让人觉得有其他可能
Well, you know, that makes it sound like it could go either way.
我不能左右她的决定
I can't tell her what to do.
我只希望你告诉她真相
I just want you to tell her the truth.
拖延时间对这个家庭太残忍了
Dragging this out is so hard on this family.
希望你好好想想
Just think about it.
劳拉  你真迷人
Lara, you're so beautiful.
我有经常赞美你吗
Did I tell you often enough?
我只想说
I just wanna say that I'm...
对不起
I'm sorry.
过来
Hello, there. Come here.
我今晚没心情陪你疯
I'm not in the mood for crazy tonight.
好孩子
Good boy.
我猜这对你来说也不容易吧  毛绒裤先生
I guess this isn't easy for you, huh, Mr. Fuzzypants?
遇见这样的家庭
Meeting a family like this?
你需要抱抱吗
Do you need a cuddle?
今晚有人需要抱抱吗
Somebody need a cuddle tonight?
好了
Okay.
只属于咱俩的特别享受哦
This is a special treat just for us.
别说出去了
Don't tell.
悲催的是  我无人可说
Sadly, I've got no one to tell.
感觉如何
How does that feel, huh?
非常难过
Very, very sad.
晚安
Good night.
我爱你
I love you.
劳拉
Lara.
劳拉  醒醒
Lara, wake up.
你想当我的发型师吗
Are you trying to be my hairdresser?
你好
Hello?
让他上来
Send him right up.
你来卖公司的吗
Do you have a company to sell?
不  大楼开幕仪式今晚举行
No, the tower opening's tonight
我没在名单上看见你的名字
and I didn't see your name on the list.
我不太喜欢抛头露面
I'm not getting out much.
你能来我们荣幸之至
We'd love to have you.
你们当然会了
I'm sure you would.
劳拉  我们都很想念汤姆
Lara, we all miss Tom very much.
也许我没有立场说这话  但你得知道
And maybe it's not my place to say this, but you have to know.
-他不会醒来了  -妈妈
- He's not coming back. - Mom?
回你的房间  丽贝卡
Go back to your room, Rebecca.
他在说什么
What is he talking about?
收拾一下准备去上学了好吗  甜心
Just get ready for school, okay, sweetie?
你在胡说些什么
You don't know what you're talking about.
医生们说他还有机会
The doctors say he has a chance.
我理解  如果我是你
I understand. If I were you,
我会不惜一切代价让他活下来
I would do anything to keep him alive.
-但他可能会昏迷好几个月  -我可以等
- But this could go on for months. - I can wait.
或者数年  甚至永远都醒不过来
Or years. And he never wakes up.
丽贝卡  她需要哀悼父亲
And Rebecca, she needs to mourn,
可如果她一直等待永远不会回来的父亲
she can't do that if she's waiting
那她也永远尽不了孝了
for a father who's never coming home.
伊恩  不要
Ian, don't...
不要
No!
快把它弄走
Get this off of me!
求你了  把这畜生弄走
Please! Get this beast off of me.
好了  进笼子里去
All right, in the cage.
我做错什么了
What did I do?
你要进笼子里去
You are going into the cage.
这就是个野猫  你得把它送去动物收容所
That cat is feral, and you need to take it to the pound.
这可是新西服
This is a brand new suit!
就算它不挠你  我也会亲自动手
He just clawed you before I could.
-劳拉  -我可不是傻瓜
- Lara... - I am not an idiot.
你来这可不是因为关心我
You're not here because you care about me
丽贝卡或者汤姆
or about Rebecca or about Tom.
我才不会拔掉我丈夫的供氧插头来助纣为虐
And I am not unplugging my husband to help your bottom line.
再见  妈妈
Bye, Mom.
等等亲爱的  我送你去学校
Wait, honey, I'll walk you to school.
不用了  妈妈
No, it's okay, Mom.
几个街区而已  我已经11岁了
It's only a couple of blocks and I'm 11.
好吧
Okay.
我懂  你想保护丽贝卡
I understand. You want to protect Rebecca.
而我想保护公司
And I want to protect the company.
但我们都需要同一样东西
But we both need the same thing.
不送  伊恩
Goodbye, Ian.
我干洗好的衣服呢
Where's my dry cleaning?
考克斯先生  你该上塔了
Mr. Cox, you're scheduled at the tower.
我知道  告诉董事会我迟点到
Yeah, I know. Tell the Board I'm running late.
-他们都在布兰德先生的办公室  -什么
- Oh, they're in Mr. Brand's office. - What?
不过我把你和活动策划人的会面时间提前了
But I moved up your meeting with the event planner.
你们不是应该在大楼里吗
Why aren't you at the tower?
-你说要开会  -我没说
- You called a meeting. - I didn't call a meeting.
是大卫召集的会议
David called the meeting.
你打算通知我的吗
Were you gonna tell me?
他说他只需要董事会成员
He said he just needed the Board.
猫的神秘论
你想明白了
You figured it out.
董事会成员在哪里
Where's the Board?
我让他们去大厦了
I sent them ahead to the tower.
很抱歉他们错过了你的会议
Sorry they missed your meeting.
没关系  我们去那里开吧
That's okay. We'll do it there.
我们会进行一次投票
We're gonna have a little vote.
是啊  你知道吗  你不会参加开幕式
Yeah, you know, you're not going to the opening.
-真的吗  -没错  布兰德先生不再为我们工作了
- Really? - Yeah. Mr. Brand no longer works for us.
他说得对  这个公司是我的
He's right. I own the company.
还不是  请把他护送出去
Not yet. Please escort him off the property.
别碰我
Don't touch me.
伊恩  你这样做  我会带着一队律师来找你的
Ian, you do this, I will come at you with an army of lawyers.
请便  告我啊
Go ahead. Sue me.
等明天我们都有钱了再告
Do it tomorrow when we're both rich.
你真的以为用几个保镖
Do you really think you can
就能占有火兰德吗
steal FireBrand with a couple of bouncers?
你觉得你父亲的一张条子就能阻止我吗
And you think you can stop me with a note from Daddy?
你父亲就要死了  你丢掉了他的公司
Your father's dying. You lost his company.
到最后  你也成不了汤姆·布兰德
At the end of the day, you're not Tom Brand.
喵金斯宠物店
看看谁回来了
Look who's back.
我就知道你会回来的
I knew you'd be back.
看谁来了
Look who's here.
我能为你做什么  小寿星
What can I do for you, birthday girl?
我想要你收回这只猫
I want you to take the cat back.
他做什么了
What's he done?
他很好  只是...
He's been great. It's just...
我觉得他们可能想把他送走
I think they might wanna take him away
也许他最好回到这里
and maybe he'd be better off back here.
我经常收到退回来的猫
I get returns all the time.
有些猫就是不喜欢它们的新家
Some cats just don't take to their new family.
我见到你爸爸时  本来希望你们能中意它
When I met your father, I hoped it would work out.
我知道这有点蠢  但是有时我觉得
I know it's stupid, but sometimes I feel
我爸爸在通过那只猫在关照我
like my dad's looking out for me through the cat.
你想他了
You miss him.
是的  我太爱我爸爸了
I do. I love my dad so much.
他也爱你
And he loves you,
但是爱一个人光说是不够的
but it's not enough to say you love someone.
你得表现出来  有时
You have to show it. Sometimes,
爱意味着牺牲
love means sacrifice.
你得表现出来
You have to show it.
你到我家的时候  你跟他说话了
When you came to the house, you were talking to him.
这是我的工作  我是个猫语者
It's what I do. I'm a cat whisperer.
没错  但是你像跟人一样跟他说话
Yeah, but you were talking to him like he was a person.
这只猫是我爸爸吗
Is this cat my dad?
珀金斯  听着  你得告诉她
Perkins, listen. You have to tell her.
-你觉得呢  -其实
- What do you think? - Well,
他让我感觉我爸爸就在这里
he makes me feel like my
那感觉甚至比以前更强烈
dad's still around more than he ever was before.
有时候
Sometimes,
我几乎希望我的爸爸能更像这只猫
I almost wish my daddy was more like the cat.
但我真的希望我爸爸能回来
But I really just want my daddy back.
失陪一下
Excuse me a minute.
我给你看样东西
I'm gonna show you something.
马上回来
I'll be right back.
等等
Wait.
你应该跟我们在一起
You should stay with us.
猫的生活好太多了
A cat's life is so much better.
谢谢  但还是算了
Thanks, but no thanks.
我们冷漠  自私  但还是被人宠爱
We're cold, selfish, and people still love us.
我不想变成那样
That's not who I wanna be.
三只酷猫
Three cool cats
能跟我跳支舞吗
May I have this dance?
坐在一部旧车的角落
Parked on the corner in a beat-up car
瓜分一块五分钱的糖
Dividing up a nickel candy bar
吹嘘着它们有多敏捷
Talking all about how sharp they are
这三只酷猫
These three cool cats
三个酷酷的小妞
Three cool chicks
安全
Clear.
丽贝卡会杀掉我的
Rebecca's gonna kill me.
你好
Hello.
-"我要中间那个妞"  -"我要最小那个妞"
- "I want that middle chick!" - "I want that little chick!"
"给我留一个"
"Hey, man, save one chick for me!"
三个酷酷的小妞
Three cool chicks
一切都好吗
Hey, everything all right?
三只酷猫坠入爱河
And three cool cats really fell in love
但是三个酷酷的小妞耍了三只酷猫
But three cool chicks made three fools of these
三只酷猫
Three cool cats
你还想退回这只猫吗
You still wanna return the cat?
不
No.
如果你想要你爸爸回来  你得走了
If you want your dad back, you should get going.
我觉得他时间不够了
I think he might be running out of time.
爸爸  当他们今晚开放大厦的时候...
Dad, when they open the tower tonight...
把头低下
Get down.
我们观察不到任何大脑活动
We're not seeing any cerebral activity at all.
我不想让你们抱有错误的希望
I just don't want to give you false hope.
他有可能再也醒不来了
There's a possibility he's not coming back.
妈妈  爸爸还在这里
Mom, Dad's still here.
能让我们单独待会儿吗
Can you give us a minute?
你知道这只猫为什么这么有趣吗
You know how the cat's been acting funny?
因为他就是爸爸
Well, that's because it's Dad.
-丽贝卡  -听我说  我能证明的
- Rebecca... - Listen, I can prove it.
我们去外面说吧
Let's talk outside.
来
Come on.
妈妈  我没瞎说
Mom, I'm not making it up.
我知道你的感受  我也很想他
Oh, look, I know how you feel. I miss him, too.
你会看到的  妈妈  他真的活在那只猫的身体里
You'll see, Mommy. He's really alive in the cat.
我搞砸了  爸爸
I screwed up, Dad.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
我这辈子都在
I spent my whole life
等一个机会来让你骄傲
waiting for a sign that I was making you proud.
当这个机会到来时
When I finally got it,
我让你失望了
I let you down.
我失去了一切
I lost everything.
我无法承受
I can't live with that.
我不知道你是否还在
I don't know if you're still in there,
但是你不想错过这个的
but you won't wanna miss this.
因为我将第一次从那座大厦上跳下
'Cause I'm gonna take my first jump.
也是最后一次
And my last jump right off of that tower.
不要  大卫
No, David!
再见了  爸爸  我爱你
Goodbye, Dad. I love you.
那现在应该怎么办
So how does this work?
你得签一份放弃治疗同意书
You'll need to sign a DNR.
放弃治疗同意书
DNR?
他们要给我拔管子了
They're pulling the plug on me?
然后我们就会关掉呼吸机
And then we'll take out the respirator.
爸爸
Daddy.
妈妈  记得从前我跟爸爸跳舞的样子吗
Mom, remember how me and Dad used to dance together?
-是的  -我们做给你看  好吗
- Yeah. - Just watch, okay? We'll show you, okay?
爸爸  过来
Daddy, come here.
爸爸  爸爸
Daddy. Daddy.
我们得跳舞给妈妈看
We need to show Mommy our dance.
过来
Come here.
爸爸
Daddy.
爱意味着牺牲
Love means sacrifice.
爸爸  爸爸
Daddy! Daddy!
我将在小猫盒里度过余生
I'm spending the rest of my life in a litter box.
爸爸
Daddy.
Daddy!
爸爸  爸爸  过来  我们得给她看
Daddy! Daddy, come here! We have to show her!
-爸爸  爸爸  你在干吗  -我的宝贝
- Daddy! Daddy! What are you doing? - My baby.
亲爱的  我很抱歉
Oh, honey, I'm sorry.
谢谢  她真美  不是吗
Thank you. Isn't she beautiful?
1900英尺的玻璃与钢铁
1,900 feet of glass and steel.
你可以认为我是个喜欢用数字说话的人
Now, you can tell I'm a bit of a numbers guy,
所以  对于我  这座大厦不只是个传奇
so, for me, this tower's more than a legacy.
这里有280万平方英尺的办公空间
Its 2.8 million square feet of pristine office space.
甚至在我剪彩之前
Before I even cut a ribbon,
这幢纽约的最高建筑已出租65%
we've leased 65% of the tallest building in New York.
其余的已在洽谈中
And we're already in negotiations for the rest of it.
我们的能力远不止如此
We can be so much more.
本公司的能力不仅是其各部分的总和
But this company is greater than the sum of its parts.
在去年  不但在房地产
Beyond real estate, in the last year,
在其它产业的收益也相当可观
we've enjoyed record earnings.
全球性零售业
Global retail.
但在发表重大消息之前
But before we move on with our big announcement,
一位特别嘉宾想说几句
we have a special guest who'd like to say a few words.
请欢迎爱德华兹市长
Please welcome Mayor Edwards.
谢谢你  伊恩
Thank you, Ian.
纽约
New York...
我们去告诉爸爸我们有多爱他
We're gonna tell Daddy how much we love him.
大卫
David?
我想稍用片刻
I like to take a moment of...
快来人  让我进去
Wake up in there. Let me in.
致敬让一切成为可能的梦想家
For the dreamer who made all this possible.
大卫·布兰德
Tom Brand.
交回给考克斯先生发言
Now I'm gonna turn this back to Mr. Cox.
我们都希望汤姆能够出席  但总得有人剪彩
We all wish Tom was here, but someone's gotta cut the ribbon.
拜托
Oh, come on!
等等
Wait!
谢天谢地你找到了它
Thank goodness you found him.
这玩意是你家的
That thing is yours?
它是毛绒裤先生  总是逃跑
That's Mr. Fuzzypants. He keeps escaping.
毛绒裤算什么名字
What kind of name is Fuzzypants?
拜托
Please.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你这个小胡迪尼
You little Houdini.
它不会再烦你  我保证
He won't bother you anymore. I promise.
它想抓我
He tried to scratch me.
那一定把你吓坏了
That must have been so scary for you.
毛绒裤
Fuzzypants.
谢谢你
Thank you.
刚才真是大胆之举  布兰德先生
That was some bold move you made back there, Mr. Brand.
谢谢你  珀金斯
Thank you, Perkins.
要是我的话
If it was me,
就会留在医院
I'd have stayed at the hospital.
看来我要搬到你店里了
Guess I'm moving into your shop.
不
No,
因为你撑不住了
'cause you're not gonna make it.
什么  等等
What? Wait!
等等  这里最精彩
Wait, this is the best part.
-我们该联系动物管制所吗  -不
- Should we call animal control? - No.
我们有泰瑟枪
We got Tasers.
对  动手吧
Right. Let's do this.
好嘞  猫咪  站着别动
All right, kitty, just stand still.
悲哀的是我开除不了你们
The sad thing is I'll never get to fire you.
我们要红爆互联网了
We're gonna break the Internet.
对不起  对不起
Sorry! Sorry!
你一定要调到最大档吗
Did you have to set it to boil?
看  笨蛋
Look, you idiot.
天啊
Oh, God.
楼顶有个男人
We got a man on the roof.
我们需要消防员  医护人员
We are gonna need fire, paramedics...
还有动物管制
And animal control.
楼顶有个男人  楼顶有个男人
We got a man on the roof. We got a man on the roof.
在楼顶上的是谁
Who's on the roof?
他要跳下来
He's going to jump!
突发新闻  一名男子在火兰德大楼顶层
大卫
David.
想都别想
Don't even think about it.
先生  从那里下来
Sir, get down from there.
离开边架
Step away from the ledge.
大卫  等等
David, wait!
火兰德公司
毛绒裤先生
Mr. Fuzzypants?
我的儿子
My son...
自始至终都是男子汉
You were a man all along.
喵  好疼
Meow, that hurt.
-汤姆  汤姆  -爸爸
- Tom? Tom? - Dad.
宝贝  我好想你
Oh, baby. Oh, I missed you so much.
很高兴看到汤姆的精神依然存在
Well, it's good to see Tom's spirit alive and well.
一旦安保处理好
As soon as security takes care of this...
拜托
Come on.
各位  晚上好
Good evening, everybody.
我听说伊恩不愿提起芝加哥
So, I hear Ian doesn't want to talk about Chicago.
我们也许没有最高的建筑
You know, we may not have the tallest building,
但我们确实拥有
but we do have the tallest building
定点跳伞的最高建筑
anyone has ever BASE jumped off.
让我们用掌声欢迎大卫·布兰德
Let's hear it for David Brand.
我很荣幸宣布明天  火兰德公司
And I'm proud to announce that tomorrow, FireBrand...
火兰德公司一直是家族生意
FireBrand has always been a family business
没什么能改变这点
and nothing is going to change that.
我看到董事们均在场
I see the Board's all here.
我们投票表决吧
Let's take a vote.
百分之五十一股份反对上市
Fifty-one percent against going public.
-你被开除了  -祝你好运
- And you're fired. - Good luck.
非常感谢
Thank you very much!
女士们先生们  伊恩·考克斯
Ian Cox, ladies and gentlemen.
为他鼓掌
Give the little guy a hand.
劳拉
Lara?
大卫  大卫  他醒了
David. David, he's awake.
-我是  -你爸爸醒了
- Yep. - Your dad's awake.
好的  我立刻过来
Okay, I'll be right there.
重大新闻  火兰德大楼隆重开幕
欢迎回来  爸爸
Welcome back, Dad.
不  我应付得来证监会
No, I can handle the SEC.
-帮我联系高盛集团  -先生
- Just get me on the phone with Goldman... - Sir...
-你还是挂了吧  -你说什么
- You might want to hang up. - Excuse me?
你不会喜欢打这通电话的结果
You're not going to like where this call is going.
谢谢  抱歉  某个疯子而已
Thank you. Sorry, some nutcase.
听着  我们依然可以把他告上法庭
Listen, we can still take him to court.
伊恩
Ian...
Ian?
老实说
Gotta be honest.
我不知道你怎么从此脱身
I don't know how you're gonna get out of this.
我讨厌猫
I hate cats.
这就是为何如此完美
That's what makes this so perfect.
你们可能想听到  我学懂了些道理
You probably want to hear that I've learned something,
我改变了
that I've changed...
我依然觉得猫是可怕的野兽
Well, I still think cats are horrible beasts
要是它们没食物了
that would eat you in your sleep
就趁你睡觉吃掉你
if they ran out of food.
它们绝对是自私的动物
They're selfish animals. That's for sure.
但我不是它们的一员
But I'm not one of them.
喵金斯宠物店
再也不是
Not anymore.
安静  闭嘴
Be quiet. Shush.
布兰德先生
Mr. Brand.
你看起来焕然一新
You look like a new man.
有什么需要我效劳的
What can I do for you?
我知道毛绒裤无法替代
I know we can't replace Fuzzypants,
但我们在考虑
but we were wondering...
如果你这里有小狗
If you have any dogs.
没
No.
但就在昨天  一位老朋友过来
But only yesterday, an old friend stopped by.
用完了它的其中八条命
Used up eight of his lives,
它还告诉我
and he tells me
它想跟你一起
he'd like to spend his last life
共度余生
with you.
毛绒裤
Fuzzypants.
所以是不能养狗了
So, that's a no on the dog, then.